Peter Richardson

Astoria, Oregon, USA pxrich@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/pxrich

portfolio: fjord.style/case-studies

Senior Product Designer with special focus on prototyping, demos, and data/interface R&D seeks remote design leadership x IC role that includes research-led product design, mentoring, and exploration. Mediates between Design and Engineering; fluent in both.

Experience

Senior Product Designer

IAMPulse / Okta

Aug 2021 - Jan 2023

Principal product designer for a security-focused startup inside of Okta, focused on research, design, and prototyping. Collaborated across product, engineering, and design to create the startup's core product, a SaaS app that allowed enterprise security administrators to visualize and preview complex, cascading interactions in IAM (Identity and Access Management) configurations. Created core navigation interface design language in Figma; implemented it in React.

Senior Visualization Engineer

Esri

Apr 2020 - Jul 2021

Cartographic data visualization and interface research and design at the Esri R&D Center. Worked with product and design teams on the development and launch of a design and component system based on Web Components, with prototype work in stencil.js.

Product Designer

Snap Inc.

Mar 2018 - Sep 2019

Software design and development for a proprietary mapping library to support flagship web-based social product.

Web Graphics Team Lead/Graphics Engineer

Mapzen / Samsung Research America

2014 - 2018

Core contributor to the development of a 3D mapping library in a startup environment as part of Samsung's investment in open-source mapping research and development. Led interface R&D and prototyping for the Tangram web mapping library (WebGL and JavaScript); built out documentation, case studies/demos, and promotional content. Brought in as Mapzen's first graphics hire, promoted to lead Web Graphics team.

Technical Director

Freelance

2001 - 2014

Contracted as an animator, designer, director, and producer on corporate, industrial, commercial, and art projects for animation, video game, and advertising studios in New York, London, Los Angeles, Portland, and San Francisco, working primarily in Maya and After Effects.

Assistant Technical Director

ESC Entertainment

Jan 2003 - Nov 2003

Worked with technical directors creating and refining 3D effects for *Matrix*: *Revolutions* feature film.

Interface Developer

Sapient

2000 - 2001

Developed enterprise web applications for a large internet consultancy.

Education

University of Oklahoma School of Visual Arts

Bachelor of Arts, Media

Focus on 3D animation